A fairy tale for troubled times.
The Shape of Water is a drama, fantasy, romance
film directed by Guillermo del Toro.
An other-worldly story, set against the backdrop of Cold War era America circa 1962, where a mute janitor working at a
lab falls in love with an amphibious man being held captive there and devises a plan to help him escape.
Elisa Esposito, played by Sally Hawkins.
Richard Strickland, played by Michael Shannon.
Giles, played by Richard Jenkins.
Zelda Fuller, played by Octavia Spencer.
Dr. Robert Hoffstetler, played by Michael Stuhlbarg.
Amphibian Man, played by Doug Jones.
The Shape of Water is a 2017 period romantic dark fantasy film directed and produced by
Guillermo del Toro, who co-wrote the screenplay with Vanessa Taylor.
It stars Sally Hawkins, Michael Shannon, Richard Jenkins, Doug
Jones, Michael Stuhlbarg, and Octavia Spencer.
Set in 1962 Baltimore, Maryland, the film follows a mute cleaner at a high-security government laboratory who falls in love with a
captured humanoid amphibian creature and decides to help him escape from death at the hands of an evil colonel.
Filming took place on location in Ontario, Canada, from August to November 2016.
The Shape of Water was screened as part of the main competition in the 74th Venice International
Film Festival, where it premiered on August 31, 2017, and was awarded the Golden Lion.
It was also screened at the 2017 Toronto International Film Festival.
It began a limited release in two theaters in New York City on December 1, 2017,
before expanding wide on December 22, and grossed $195 million worldwide.
The Shape of Water was widely acclaimed by critics, who lauded its acting, screenplay,
direction, visuals, production design, cinematography, and musical score.
The American Film Institute selected it as one of the top ten films of 2017.
The film was nominated for a leading thirteen awards at the 90th Academy Awards, winning four, including Best Picture and Best Director, and received
numerous other accolades; it was the second fantasy film to win Best Picture, after The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King (2003).
A novelization by del Toro and Daniel Kraus was published on March 6, 2018.
The film explores themes of government, fairy tale,
cold war, supernatural, baltimore, usa.
The tone is emotional.